[The Heir]
[Episode 26]
Fourth Sister-in-law.
Why did you call me here
so suddenly?
What is this?
What?
You just asked someone
to bring this hairpin to Yunniang
last month.
And now you don't recognize it?
Fourth Sister-in-law.
H-How did this hairpin
end up in your hands?
You have the nerve to ask me?
In front of Third Brother and Chunhua,
you pretend to be a decent person.
But behind their backs,
you went to find
your mistress and child again,
even providing for them.
If I give this hairpin to Third Brother,
he will flay you alive.
Have mercy, Fourth Sister-in-law.
If this gets out,
I won't be able to survive.
It's all Li Zhen's fault.
If it weren't for her,
how could I be living
such a miserable life in the Li family?
Since you hate her so much,
I'll give you a chance.
As long as
you have the guts and capability
to do something for me,
I promise to make her leave the Li family
forever.
Well, I...
How would I have the guts
or the capability?
If you succeed,
I won't just find you a house in Huizhou,
bringing your mistress and child over
to reunite with you,
but I'll also give you a good opportunity
to make a name for yourself
in the Li family.
No one will look down on you anymore.
If you want to achieve anything
in the Li family in the future,
it won't be difficult.
Fourth Sister-in-law,
the thing you want me to do—
how confident are you about it?
In this kind of matter,
it's about who is willing to risk it all.
In this family,
only one of us
can stay.
As long as you do as I say,
this matter will never be exposed.
I'll take responsibility if it does.
However,
if you're willing
to live a spineless life forever,
I'll just take it
as I misjudged you.
From Chunhua to Li Jingdong,
they guard against me
like thiefs all day!
I'm a man.
If I live like this
for the rest of my life,
what's the point?
As for this matter,
I agree to it.
I am at your command,
Fourth Sister-in-law.
The traditional materials used for Shize Ink
are different from those of Li Ink.
Especially the Isinglass.
Since it's not commonly used for Li Ink,
we didn't have much in stock before.
Now that the orders have gone up,
I was thinking
we need to prepare some more.
You are right.
There's not enough time now,
and the ink workshop
doesn't have enough hands.
I heard from Grandfather
that Isinglass
is also commonly used
by carpenters for varnishing.
Why don't we select
one or two reliable sources
and purchase some Isinglass from outside?
What do you think?
That's the safest way.
Then it's settled.
Okay.
Aunt Chunhua?
What brings you here?
Aunt,
this is Songluo tea.
Have a taste.
Aunt,
there's no need to be formal between us.
Just speak your mind.
Well...
Decai...
He wants to come back to work at Li Ink.
Zhen, please don't misunderstand.
I know your concerns,
and I didn't really forgive him.
He asked me to plead with you.
I thought about it for a long time.
I don't want to cause you more trouble.
But since the last incident,
I've been observing him,
and he has indeed become much more
honest and obedient.
I figured,
rather than letting him
stay at home and overthink,
it's better to give him a job
at the ink workshop
to settle his mind.
Aunt, you are my elder.
Normally,
I shouldn't speak ill of others
in front of you.
But regarding Uncle,
I've seen it all with my own eyes.
He lied to you like that before,
and now
he's forcing us to give him a chance.
Honestly,
it makes me
feel uncomfortable.
I feel uncomfortable too.
But Decai is Run's father after all.
I can't bear for Run
to see his father trapped at home all day,
living such a pathetic life.
Run is still young now,
so it's fine that he doesn't know.
But when he grows up,
he will inevitably be mocked by others.
In that case,
let him come.
Really?
You can't get rid of him
for the time being.
It's better
to put him in the ink workshop,
keeping a close eye on him.
Let him start as a low-level ink-maker,
wearing down his temper a bit.
If he truly repents in the future
and wants to make ink properly,
I will discuss with Uncle Jingdong
how to arrange a position for him.
Thank you, Zhen.
Since you are new to the ink workshop,
start with twisting lamp wicks.
Nowadays, making ink in the ink workshop
requires a large number of lamp wicks.
You won't be exposed to the smoke here,
and it doesn't take much effort either.
Zhen.
Don't you think this job is
a bit of a
waste of my talents?
How about I help with ink mixing
or manage the warehouse?
In the ink workshop,
you should call me Manager Zhen.
Since Aunt Chunhua
entrusted you to my care,
once you enter the ink workshop,
you must follow my rules.
Working here requires patience.
Twisting lamp wicks
will help
calm your greedy,
restless nature.
Once you are tempered,
I will be willing to guide you through
every step of ink-making in the future.
But if I find you
having the slightest disloyalty,
let alone the ink workshop,
the entire Li family
will have no place for you.
Uncle,
do you understand
what I said?
So, can you do this job
or not?
I can. Of course I can.
Manager Zhen, you're right.
If I, Li Decai, let Chunhua down again,
or show any disloyalty,
may I be struck by lightning
and die a horrible death.
I...
Uncle Jingdong.
Where is that bastard?
Don't worry, Uncle Jingdong.
I've arranged for him
to twist lamp wicks for now.
Good.
I just don't believe
that Li Decai
can behave himself in the ink workshop.
To be honest,
I don't believe it either.
But rather than worrying all day,
it's better to keep him
in the ink workshop
and keep a close eye on him.
Zhen,
this was originally the Sixth Branch's
own family matter.
Sorry for causing you trouble again.
I'll be leaving for the pine yard
in another county tomorrow.
It will take at least 10 days.
Please take good care of the family
and the ink workshop.
Rest assured, Uncle Jingdong.
I will do my best.
It's tough working away from home.
Take care of yourself.
Doggie.
This is the Isinglass merchant
that Manager Zhen and I selected.
Go make a trip
and have them deliver the Isinglass
as soon as possible.
Okay, I'll go then.
Rest assured.
My isinglass is perfectly fine.
Why...
Why are you testing it again?
Is there a problem with testing it again?
There's no problem.
Manager Zhen.
This isinglass was all
prepared according to
Steward Shao's requirements.
We use fish from our own farm.
As soon as they are caught, we extract
the bladders and boil them into isinglass.
Within a hundred li of Huizhou,
you can ask around,
and you won't find any better isinglass
than mine.
You might not know, sir,
but when Li Ink purchases glue,
we inspect every barrel without exception.
We take turns inspecting them,
so we can be fully assured, right?
Of course.
Put it in storage.
You'll surely be satisfied.
Come on, give me the list.
Come with me to get it stamped.
Alright.
This way.
Everyone, put in a bit more effort.
This glue is actually not bad.
Fang.
The ink should be thoroughly mixed.
Put some more effort into it.
Zhen.
This ink will probably need a whole night
to be mixed.
Why don't you go back, get some sleep,
and come back in the morning
to inspect it?
No, I'm not at ease.
I'd better stay with you.
The rainy season
came a bit early this year.
The glue goes bad easily.
Everyone!
Thanks for your hard work!
We have to work through the night!
Please put in a bit more effort!
-Okay.
-Okay!
The smell here is really bad.
You're just waiting if you stay here.
Why don't you go inside?
I'll call you when it's done.
Okay, I'll go inside for a bit.
I'll take over for you in a while.
Okay.
Thanks for your hard work, Zhengshen.
Don't worry.
Why are you here?
Look.
My mother made this?
Why did she have you deliver it?
I ran into your mother
on my way to the ink workshop.
She said she guessed
you'd be staying up all night here,
so she made some chicken soup for you.
So I volunteered
to be an errand boy
and bring it to you.
But...
how did you know your mother
made this soup?
I could smell it.
When my mother makes soup,
she likes to add tangerine peel
and astragalus.
I grew up drinking it,
so I could recognize it
from the smell alone.
You have a good nose.
Of course.
In an ink-making family like ours,
we had to practice smelling
and identifying ink
blindfolded from a young age.
When we were kids,
Zhengshen and my brother
hated it the most.
But I was especially good at it.
I was always winning praise
from my grandfather
and Seventh Grandmother.
Back then, every time I guessed right,
Seventh Grandmother would give me
a piece of sugar cake.
At first, I trained my nose so hard
just for the sugar cakes.
When Seventh Grandmother wakes up,
I'll show her the Origin Ink
and Shize Ink.
Then I'll ask her for two more pieces
of sugar cake.
There used to be
ancient lacquer-soot ink and Fu Jin Ink.
Now there's the Origin Ink and Shize Ink.
I believe that in the future,
you'll make even more
and even better ink.
By then, Seventh Old Madam
will be able to see them all.
Speaking of ink-making,
it's a coincidence.
When you first came to Huizhou,
I just started learning to make ink.
Up to now,
I have made 4 kinds of ink.
Old ink makers,
including my grandfather,
at most,
only make a few good pieces
of ink in their lifetime.
All these opportunities I had
were because of you.
Then you should say
my judgment is one of a kind.
I bring luck to whoever I invest in.
Who was it that,
because of the Tribute Ink incident,
even lost his own job?
You should just stay by my side
and think about how to make a comeback.
But even if
you're reinstated in the future,
we can still
do Shize Ink business together.
We'll sell Shize Ink
all the way to the Capital.
If we can sell it to a Number One Scholar,
we'll make a fortune.
Alright, alright, I'll be waiting.
What's that smell?
What's wrong?
Everyone, stop!
Stop!
Stop, all of you!
Indeed.
Why has all the glue gone bad?
Zhen,
I checked it.
The cowhide glue is fine.
It's just the Isinglass—
this stuff is especially sensitive
to moisture.
Could it be the rain?
This little rain is fine.
Besides, these walls were mixed
with moisture-resistant Sichuan pepper.
Even if the floor had dampness rising,
it wouldn't turn out like this overnight.
All of the glue was checked
bucket by bucket
by me and Steward Shao
before being stored.
How could they suddenly spoil?
And the lock is fine.
I checked it. No sign of tampering.
And last time, it was Steward Shao and I
who locked it together.
Zhengshen, Master Qi,
all the mixed ink and boiled glue tonight
must not be discarded.
Also,
have the workers
who were making ink tonight
stay here for the night for now.
Until this matter is investigated clearly,
it must be kept strictly confidential.
Don't worry. Here's the key.
This is serious.
Shize Ink is waiting for our delivery.
Manager Zhen,
we must quickly figure out a way
to remedy this in time.
As for how to remedy this,
you don't need to worry about it, Uncle.
I'll figure it out.
You were the one who inspected the glue,
and you were the one
who signed off on the order.
What else is there to investigate?
Are you going to investigate
who forged your handwriting
or who cast a spell on you?
I inspected the glue.
There was no problem
before it went into the warehouse.
That's right.
Manager Zhen and I inspected it together.
The glue was of good quality
when it arrived.
Someone must have tampered with it
after it was stored.
We really need
to investigate this thoroughly.
That's right. I saw it too.
Then let's investigate
those who have the keys to the warehouse.
Then the truth will naturally come out.
The keys to the warehouse—
Steward Shao, Uncle Jingdong, and I
each have one.
There.
Sister-in-law,
our family has always been fair.
Now that Third Brother is not here,
you are the only one
who can take charge here.
As a manager, Zhen
is clearly incompetent.
In my opinion,
we should revoke
her managerial power first.
Jiangyue.
Then see how big this mess is
and how to fix it.
Fourth Aunt,
before it is thoroughly investigated,
I will not
hand over my managerial power.
Zhen.
Eldest Aunt.
The top priority right now
is to find out the truth,
replenish the raw materials,
and rush out this batch of Shize Ink.
For the sake of this ink,
I can't step down.
After the ink is delivered,
if it is indeed proven
to be my negligence,
I won't need anyone to say anything.
I will ask Seventh Grandmother
for punishment myself.
Zhen,
if we remake the ink,
is there still time?
If we remedy it right away,
we can still make it.
Good.
Usually, in this family,
my words don't carry much weight.
But today, with Third Brother
not being here,
this family needs a man
to step up and take charge,
so we can discuss this properly, right?
Stop talking about unrelated things.
Just get straight to the point.
Decai,
if you have something to say,
just say it.
I've heard these past few days
that ever since our family
used the dug-out rosin oil to make ink,
and the news spread,
people everywhere have been imitating us.
Those who do it well
number quite a few.
It just so happens
that with the managers of these places,
I am somewhat acquainted.
Time is tight now.
Why don't you let me make a trip
and buy a batch of ink
similar to Shize Ink
to solve the urgent problem?
That seems like a good idea.
Uncle, you've already resigned
from the merchant job.
I didn't expect you to still be
so well-informed about the news outside.
This is the only way.
Sister-in-law,
if you think
this method is feasible,
please give me some money.
By the way,
it might be inappropriate to talk to them
with my current identity.
If we want to make a deal,
please lend me the seal for a few days,
Manager Zhen.
You've been in the ink workshop
for less than half a month
and haven't twisted many lamp wicks.
So your mind has been all on this?
I'll lay it out here today.
The current head
of the Li family is me, Li Zhen.
You won't get a single penny you want.
And don't even think about
the family seal.
Shize Ink is Shize Ink.
Delivering other ink would be fraud.
If we can't deliver the ink,
I'd rather lose money
than do this self-deceiving business.
Manager Zhen!
Manager Zhen.
Mr. Zhang went to the ink workshop
with the Education Official.
The Education Official?
Why did they go to the ink workshop?
They heard there was a problem
with Shize Ink
and came to demand an explanation.
Heard?
Again?
Manager Zhen, you are here.
My Lord, you visited so early.
I, Li Zhen, Manager of Li Ink,
failed to welcome you.
Please forgive me.
Manager Li.
The Shize Ink developed by Li Ink
[Education Official of Huizhou]
has been benefiting
the poor students in Huizhou.
Shize Ink has become
the first choice for Huizhou students
taking the autumn imperial examination.
This was supposed to be a great tale.
However, I heard from
Mr. Zhang and the others
that there is a problem
with the Shize Ink you are making.
I personally named
and recommended this ink.
If something really goes wrong,
how am I supposed
to explain it to the students?
Steward Shao,
is there a problem with our ink?
No.
Doggie, did you hear anything?
Well...
we don't even know about it.
Where did you
hear this rumor from?
Li Zhen,
the news
came right from your ink workshop.
Our ink workshop?
So Mr. Zhang
even knows someone in our ink workshop?
Who is it?
It's none of your business
who I heard it from.
Just tell me
if the glue you use to make the ink
has a problem.
Is all the Shize Ink
you made faulty?
If the Education Official's reputation
is ruined because of this,
and the students start protesting,
can you bear the consequences?
This is absolutely untrue.
My Lord,
our Li Ink has a reputation in Huizhou
for over a hundred years.
We have never done business in bad faith.
I, Li Zhen, assure you that
when the delivery date arrives,
Li Ink will deliver the exact amount.
Since you say
the ink can be delivered as promised,
then take us all to see the ink we ordered
and check if it's really fine.
Please.
My Lord.
My Lord, you might not know,
but we have a rule in ink-making.
The ink-making area is important,
so no unrelated personnel are allowed inside.
What a stupid rule!
I think you are just feeling guilty.
Our Manager Zhen
hasn't let you in yet.
My Lord.
You might not know,
but the ink-making process is complex.
A slight mistake can cause it to spoil.
Besides, the delivery date
hasn't arrived yet.
There's no reason
to come and make things difficult for us.
If you force your way in
and the ink really spoils,
then how am I supposed to
explain it to you, My Lord?
If the students start protesting,
will they go to the Education Official,
or to you, Mr. Zhang?
Mr. Zhang.
The ink workshop has its own rules.
Let's not break them.
Thank you, My Lord.
The autumn imperial examination
is not a trifling matter.
Please look out for yourselves.
Don't make things difficult for me.
I understand!
Farewell, My Lord.
Can you understand everything in school?
Sister-in-law.
I have something to say to you.
What is it?
What exactly are you planning?
I heard that girl even dared
to deceive the Education Official.
She managed to bluff through today,
but what if
she can't deliver the goods in the future?
Are you just going to watch
the Li family be dragged down by her?
I understand what you mean,
but we should trust Zhen.
If we trust her,
this family will be ruined.
Sister-in-law,
I may have made mistakes,
but I am
a daughter-in-law of the Li family.
My heart is with the Li family.
Li Zhen is not.
She is someone
we kicked out of the family.
No matter how good things are,
can she not hold a grudge in her heart?
After all, she's not our family.
You can be tolerant on the surface,
but you have to be on guard in your heart.
Then what do you think
we should do?
Call on the clan elders
and force Li Zhen to step down.
Time is tight now.
Why don't you let me make a trip
and buy a batch of ink
similar to Shize Ink
to solve the urgent problem?
Shize Ink is Shize Ink.
If we can't deliver the ink,
I'd rather lose money
than do this self-deceiving business.
Shize Ink has become
the first choice for Huizhou students
taking the autumn imperial examination.
If something really goes wrong,
how am I supposed to explain it
to the students?
Mother,
don't worry.
Even if we really have to compensate
for this order,
as long as I have hands and feet,
I can be like Zhen,
starting from making lampblack
for other ink workshops
and earning the Li family back bit by bit.
Good boy.
The most important thing for you now
is to study hard.
You don't need to worry about
anything else.
Shize Ink is different from other orders.
I actually think
what Decai said is also a way.
Even if it's not the ink of our Li family,
it's better than
having nothing to deliver.
You heard
what the Education Official said.
If we really can't deliver the ink
and affect
the autumn imperial examination,
we will go to jail.
Eldest Aunt,
think about it.
Something has just happened
in our ink workshop,
and Li Decai already had
a full set of countermeasures.
First he said he would collect other ink,
then he said we needed money,
and he even asked for our family seal.
Master Qi watches
this ink workshop very closely.
It would never leak any news.
But the Education Official
came in the blink of an eye.
Think about it carefully.
All of this is definitely related
to Li Decai.
You mean
this is all Decai's doing?
Exactly.
How is that possible?
How could he have the guts?
Even if he couldn't do it all by himself,
behind this,
there must be someone else.
You're right.
We must investigate
what needs to be investigated.
But the most important thing right now
is to deliver the ink.
You understand?
The only way now
is the idea Decai came up with.
Why won't you give it a try?
Eldest Aunt,
I've told you so much.
Why don't you still understand?
If I really listen to Li Decai,
then our Li family will truly be ruined.
Zhen,
do you not believe him,
or are you afraid
someone will take your manager position?
This management power was entrusted
personally to me by Seventh Grandmother.
If it is to be taken back,
she has to take it back herself.
I won't
hand Li Ink over to anyone else.
Eldest Aunt,
I have other things to do
at the ink workshop.
I will get back to work.
You should think about it carefully.
Zhen!
I know what happened to the glue!
Bad news.
Eldest Aunt
invited all the Li clan elders over.
Now they want you to return to
the main family to be questioned.
Elder, please.
Greetings, Elders.
Seventh Old Madam is seriously ill.
There are no elders
holding the fort at home,
and you actually made such a big mess.
If Sun hadn't told me,
Li Ink might have been ruined
in your hands.
For the long-term sake of Li Ink,
hand over the family seal.
I have just arrived here
and was lectured by you.
Please allow me to defend myself.
Regarding the Isinglass incident,
I have found out the truth.
Please make a clear judgment, Elders.
Doggie.
Sorry to trouble you, Fourth Aunt.
Well...
Thank you, Fourth Aunt.
Please look, Elders.
Regarding the Isinglass,
someone tampered with the glue bucket.
They replaced the bottom of the bucket
but didn't make it waterproof.
It has been raining continuously
these days,
and the bottom got damp,
which caused the Isinglass to rot.
Zhen.
It seems it really was
the glue merchant's doing.
Who is this person? Have they been caught?
When I went to catch him,
this person had already run away.
Now things are clear.
The Isinglass incident
was someone deliberately trying
to harm the Li family.
It's highly likely
there was an inside job.
At the ink workshop,
I have already sent people
to buy new Isinglass urgently
to rush the production of Shize Ink.
Please rest assured, Elders.
We must catch the saboteur,
but the priority now
is to deliver the ink.
I think
we should let Decai buy
ready-made ink as soon as possible.
Ensuring on-time delivery
is the most important thing.
Yes.
Wanyi,
let's stick to our agreed plan.
Eldest Aunt.
The most important thing now
is to deliver the ink.
Zhen,
why don't you hand it over for now?
Eldest Aunt,
buying other ink is like
drinking poison to quench thirst.
It will cause endless trouble.
I will absolutely not
hand the family seal over.
Just as I expected.
Li Zhen
is really stubborn and unreasonable!
Don't be angry, Elder.
Li Zhen is young.
She doesn't know
the gravity of the matter.
I think she refuses to hand over the seal
because she doesn't trust Li Decai.
I do have a solution.
Why not let Li Zhen
give the seal to Wanyi,
and have her and Decai
buy the ink together?
It will convince everyone
and solve our urgent problem.
Exactly.
I have only learned about ink
for a few days,
and I'm Li family's matrilocal son-in-law.
It's normal that Zhen
doesn't trust me.
But if Wanyi can go with me,
it will definitely
be much more appropriate.
I think this plan is feasible.
Wanyi is kind-hearted.
She has been with
the Seventh Old Madam the longest.
You handle this.
Decai,
you will assist her.
Yes.
Li Decai!
I've been too nice to you, haven't I?
Don't you know
why I don't trust you?
You kept a mistress
and secretly sold raw lacquer to make money
without Aunt Chunhua's knowledge.
If Aunt Chunhua hadn't pleaded repeatedly,
how could I let you
work at the ink workshop?
You've only been at the ink workshop
for a few days,
and then the Isinglass incident happened.
How could a traitor like you
be so kind to the Li family?
Let me ask you.
Did you and those ink merchants
collude long ago,
just waiting
to swindle the Li family's money?
Or rather,
in the Isinglass incident,
you were the one working from the inside?
Li Zhen!
You don't want to hand over
the family seal,
so you're just accusing me falsely.
Although I'm a matrilocal husband
whose words carry no weight,
I won't allow you
to wrong me for no reason!
Li Decai!
For the Li family,
I've worked my heart out
and have always been loyal.
I shouldn't have spared you
for the raw lacquer incident!
How presumptuous, Li Zhen!
How dare you use force against an elder
in front of the clan elders!
Zhen!
Tian Jiangyue,
you've been jumping up and down.
Don't think
I don't know what you're up to.
Today, you just want to use
the clan elders and Eldest Aunt
to force me to hand over the family seal
and to leave the Li family, right?
I'm telling you.
Times have changed.
I won't fulfill your wish.
If I find out you had anything to do
with what happened behind the scenes,
I won't let you off easily!
How arrogant!
Today,
according to our ancestors' rules,
we'll draft a public resolution
and dismiss you as the head of the family!
Rules of our ancestors?
What rules of our ancestors?
You elders seem to have forgotten
that our Eighth Branch
was expelled from the clan long ago.
If we really want to be particular
about it,
I'm not a member of the Li family!
And you
can't control me at all!
Preposterous!
Looks like
we brought back an ungrateful wretch!
If I am an ungrateful wretch,
then you elders
must be blinded!
May I ask you elders,
when I helped the Li family recreate
the ancient lacquer-soot ink
and was framed by them
for stealing the ink recipe,
where were you?
When this ink workshop was destroyed,
and I was trying to win back
the ink merchants
while rebuilding it,
where were you?
When the pine wilt disease was raging
and the Tian family
forcibly requisitioned pine timber,
it was I, Li Zhen,
who came up with the rosin oil solution
to help the Li family
tide over one crisis after another!
Every single one of these things—
have you forgotten them all?
When things went wrong,
I've never seen you
help the Li family even once.
But now you can't even tell
right from wrong
and side with these villains.
I'm telling you!
The Li family was personally entrusted
to me by Seventh Grandmother.
Unless she wakes up
and comes to take it back herself,
no one
shall take
this family seal seal from me!
This is outrageous!
Servants!
Seize this
disobedient girl!
Find
the family seal!
Who dares!
The entire Li clan
no longer recognizes this head.
What are you afraid of?
Get her!
Who says no one recognizes her anymore?
Uncle Jingdong?
You're back?
I, Li Jingdong,
pay my respects.
Elders,
please be seated.
I,
Li Jingdong, the eldest son
of the Sixth Branch of the Li family,
am here to make my position clear
to all the elders.
My niece, Li Zhen,
is the head of the Li family.
If anyone has a problem with that,
come to me.
Third Brother...
Have you forgotten about your leg?
Li Zhen has been expelled from the clan.
How can you stand up for her?
Yes.
She was expelled from the clan,
yet she works tirelessly
for the Li family every day
and has saved the Li family
from disaster several times.
But what about you?
Time and time again,
you have tripped her up
and slung mud at her!
Elders,
I can personally vouch
for my niece, Li Zhen.
Please give her 5 days.
By then,
she will definitely reveal the truth
and
provide a way
to deliver the order on time.
Elders,
what do you think?
What if after 5 days
there is still no explanation?
Then I will step down voluntarily
and won't make things difficult
for the clan elders.
Alright.
Let's leave it at that for today.
We'll see the result
in 5 days.
Take care, Elders.